Michael Cameron Golaski

golaskimichael@gmail.com | 724.263.4192

OVERVIEW

Motivated to solve problems in data management and analysis using analytical tools and programs to research and investigate data issues. With experience and practice in over 15 programming languages while supporting 100s of customers and employees. Developing upper-level skills in the following:

• Advanced: Python, SQL, R, Snowflake, Qlik Sense, SAS

• Intermediate: Tableau, Mathematica, C++, MATLAB, Java Script, DBT, Airflow

EDUCATION

Institute for Advanced Analytics, North Carolina State University

Masters of Science Analytics

Elon University

Bachelor of Science: Statistics, Concentration: Data Analytics Minors: Mathematics, Computer Science, Data Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist - Siemens-Healthineers

June 2022 -Present

Cary, North Carolina

- Build Dashboards to help employees research Financial and Service Reports for customers reducing time spent on tasks over 100+ hours a year based on the department
- Design an R shiny web application based on contract information and other inputs from customers which simulated millions of different Service outcomes for customer
- Overhaul Revenue processes to incorporate real time reporting; replacing monthly summaries
- Use of statistics and accounting methods to create reports for recognized and deferred revenue to help employees detect outliers in payments; decreasing the financial team's research and reporting time over 50%
- Spearhead the transition from SAS platforms to Snowflake, Azure, and other technologies, facilitating the inclusion of advanced features in older reports and tools; increased data accessibility and efficiency by 30% while lowering operational costs by \$60,000 per year
- Engineer and implement a data automation solution using Snowflake, DBT, and Airflow to schedule and generate daily reports; resulting in a 40% reduction in manual reporting tasks and saving 20+ hours weekly

Practicum: Cigna Corporation, Communication Lead

September 2021 - May 2022

- Developed a predictive model to determine the effectiveness of and response to immune checkpoint inhibitors for immunotherapy cancer treatment
- Explored and analyzed authorization, eligibility, lab, and claims data with over 90,000 records
- Visualized relationships for patient demographics versus cancer type and stage on treatment efficiency via a Tableau dashboard

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Undergraduate Research Student

January 2020 - February 2021

- Created 50+ visuals in SAS to determine if herding bias was occurring among different state polls
- Employed advanced Time Series models to track and analyze shifts in polling data, pinpointing seasonal trends and forecasting fluctuations
- Utilized Dependent T-Tests on average of poll results which indicated a strong presence of herding bias in 47 out of 50 states
- Conducted comprehensive data analysis on 48,000+ observations and 50+ variables, leading to better understanding of trends in the polls
- Manipulated the data in SAS to create more variables to help analyze the data further